Amen.
He is with the Lord.
The papal throne has become vacant.
"Aldo."
Do you think anyone will mind if I take the chessboard?
- As a memento. - Of course, take it.
He wanted you to have it.
Because we used to play a lot in the evening.
He used to say that playing chess helped him relax.
- And who won? - He did.
He was always eight steps ahead.
My deepest condolences, Aldo.
What happened?
Do you know?
No, they say he had a heart attack, but...
They warned him.
I haven't heard of that.
Yes, he didn't want anyone to know.
He was afraid that if the news spread, they would start
circulating rumors that he intended to resign.
The papal court.
Yes.
Okay.
"Janusz."
I know this is hard on you,
but we will have to prepare a detailed statement.
Who discovered the Pope's death?
I did, Your Eminence.
And what did you do afterward?
I called the Pope's doctor.
But it was too late.
What time did you make the call?
Around 11:30, Your Eminence.
We would have called you earlier, but...
My deepest condolences, Thomas.
I know His Holiness didn't have close colleagues like you and Aldo,
but I asked Janusz to stop speaking with you.
I wanted to verify all the facts.
You know how rumors spread.
I've prepared a timeline for His Holiness's last day.
And these are the latest medical reports for Pope Francis.
And who was the last to meet with him?
I believe it was me.
Father Wozniak, were you the last to meet with him?
Yes, Your Eminence Tremblay.
Record all the meetings he had that day.
They will show how much effort he exerted until his last breath.
Okay, it seems
we placed a great burden on a sick man.
The papacy is a great burden.
Especially for an old man.
Well, Dean, it seems the responsibility for the meeting falls on you.
Seal the room.
"Three weeks after the conclave convened"
The security agencies say they want to test the electronic jamming devices
- One last time, Your Eminence. - Let them do it quickly.
Is this really necessary, Willy?
Apparently so.
They say eavesdroppers can use lasers to read vibrations on glass.
Really? Let's hope none of our brethren suffer from claustrophobia.
And who knows how long we will be here?
Can you assure me that we will finish on time?
They will work all night if they have to.
It will be simple, Your Eminence. It always is.
- It's Italy, you know. - I apologize for the inconvenience.
Well, Your Eminence, I want to say this is a fair version of hell.
Don't speak blasphemy, Ray.
Hell will come tomorrow when we bring in the cardinals. [Cardinals: responsible for choosing the new pope]
How do I pronounce this word?
"Kakal," Your Eminence. It's Indian.
"Kakal." Thank you.
Archbishop Wozniak has requested to speak with Your Eminence.
I don't think that's possible. The cardinals will arrive in an hour.
- What's the matter? - He didn't specify.
I wouldn't have remembered the issue.
It's just that he seemed very upset.
Ray, we will be secluded from 6:00.
He should have come to me earlier.
Yes, Your Eminence. I will inform him of that.
No, Ray, tell him I will see him after I meet the cardinals.
The poor man will be worried about his future.
How many people have come, Willy?
103, Your Eminence Lawrence.
I wonder where Tedisco went.
- Perhaps he won't come. - It's too much to hope for.
We can wait inside if you prefer.
No, let's stay here and take in the fresh air.
Father Bellini.
"Aldo."
- Am I the last to arrive? - Not quite. How are you?
Well, as you know, in a terrible state.
Have you read the newspapers?
Apparently, they've decided that I'm the new pope.
And I agree with them.
What if I don't want the position?
No sane man would want the papacy.
It seems some of our colleagues desire the position.
What if I know deep in my heart that I am not worthy of the position?
- You deserve it more than any of us. - I'm not.
Then tell your supporters not to vote for you,
so you don't bear the burden.
And leave the position to him?
I couldn't live knowing what I had done.
Your Eminence Tedisco.
Dean Lawrence!
How are you?
I'm fine, Goffredo.
Sorry, my train was delayed from Venice.
- We've missed you. - Yes.
I'm sure of that.
But don't worry.
My friends have kept me informed.
Are you okay?
No. No one is okay at our age, right?
And you?
How do you feel with this...
new responsibility?
Is everything under control? Yes, I think so.
Your Eminence Goffredo, may I?
No!
See you later.
You're welcome. See you later, Your Eminence.
My God. It's large.
Apparently, Pope John XXIII was too fat to wear a cassock,
so they had to split the seams in the back for him to wear it.
You look tired.
All this is a duty I never thought I would have to undertake.
I thought he would outlive all of us.
Our farewell wasn't good.
I asked him for permission to resign from my position as Dean.
To join the monastery.
What was his response?
He rejected my resignation.
He said some were chosen to be shepherds
and others to manage.
Apparently I&#39;ve been selected for management.
He told me about your crisis of faith.
But you should know
that he had doubts too.
Did the Pope have doubts about God?
no.
He did not doubt the Lord.
What he has lost faith in is the church.
Father Wozniak?
In the name of the Father, the Son and the Holy Spirit.
- My last confession was four weeks ago.
- &quot;Yanush.&quot;
&quot;Yanush,&quot; I don&#39;t have time to hear your confession.
There is still a lot to do.
Have you been drinking?
What&#39;s worrying you? Tell me.
I should have come to you before.
But I promised not to say anything.
- Who did you promise to?
- Cardinal Tremblay.
&quot;Yanush,&quot; the doors will close soon and you will have to leave.
If you promised Cardinal Tremblay, then perhaps it is not right that...
The day the Pope died,
The last person he had an official appointment with was Cardinal Tremblay.
Yes, I know that.
It&#39;s on the official timeline.
The Pope excommunicated him at that meeting.
What?
He kicked him out.
Why?
For gross misconduct.
And you&#39;re telling me this now?
We&#39;re about to be isolated, Janusz.
Forgive me, but I only started hearing the rumors in the last few days.
- Any rumors?
- That he might be elected pope.
And you think it&#39;s your duty to prevent that, right?
I don&#39;t know what my duty is anymore.
Were you present at the meeting?
No, your excellency.
The Pope told me
after the meeting was over,
When we had dinner.
Shall I tell you why Eminence Tremblay was fired?
no.
He said the reasons would soon become clear.
Brigadier General Lawrence.
There is a problem.
Oh, my God.
Did someone die?
- Excuse me?
- Did we lose a cardinal?
No, Your Honor.
Looks like we got one.
I mean that literally.
Another cardinal just came.
So it seems we forgot to include Cardinal in the list.
His name was not on our list, Your Eminence.
He says he was appointed Cardinal
in secret.
No, he must be a scammer.
That&#39;s what I thought, Your Eminence.
But Archbishop Mandorf
talked to him and didn&#39;t think he was a fraud.
Well, what did you hear?
His name is &quot;Vincent Benitez&quot;, Your Eminence.
He is the Archbishop of Kabul.
Archbishop where?
&quot;Kabul.&quot; But he&#39;s Mexican.
He was appointed by the Pope last year.
Last year? So how was this kept hidden all this time?
I thought you might know about his promotion.
No, I&#39;m not.
Ray, have Eminence Bellenia join us.
Maybe he knows something about this.
- Yes, Your Eminence.
- Thank you.
He has a letter of appointment from the Pope.
Addressed to the Archdiocese of Kabul,
Which they kept secret at the request of the Pope.
Do you think he forged the letter?
Where is he now?
Cardinal in Afghanistan?
This is ridiculous.
How many Catholics are there in Afghanistan?
He was the head of the Catholic mission there.
Until he was promoted.
But how do we ensure his safety?
This is probably why the Pope wanted to keep his promotion a secret.
Well, his status is not a secret anymore.
I don&#39;t think we have a choice but to acknowledge it.
Hold on, Thomas.
Are we sure that the Pope
He was fully qualified.
When did he make this appointment?
I think this man is a cardinal, legally speaking, Aldo.
I believe he has the right to participate in the elections.
Your Eminences,
Before we eat,
I would like to introduce you to a new member of our sect,
whose existence was unknown to any of us,
Until a few hours.
The reason is because our brother became a cardinal.
Completely legal
Secretly.
The reason why he had to be appointed this way
Only God and the late Pope know.
But I think we can guess why,
Because the service our new brother was performing was a very dangerous service.
Welcome to our community
Vincent Benitez,
Cardinal Archbishop of Kabul.
Would you please bless our meal, Your Eminence?
naturally.
Bless us, O Lord, and these are your gifts,
Which we are about to eat please
Amen.
May the Lord bless all
Who can&#39;t eat this food?
And help us, O Lord, when we eat and drink
So we remember the hungry
and the thirsty
and patients
Waluhidin
And the sisters who prepared food for us
Thanks to (Christ) our Lord
Amen.
Sit down please.
This is amazing...
Here, come on.
Hey Dean!
&quot;Lawrence&quot;!
I have...
- &quot;Goffredo&quot;.
- &quot;Thomas&quot;.
Have a seat.
Have some wine.
Thanks.
You seem worried.
And we haven't even started yet.
Our new brother...
Is it true what I heard, "Afghanistan"?
Yes.
It's a testament to the power of the church's influence.
Don't you think so?
Many people of different races
joined together in their faith in the Lord.
Look around you.
Notice how everyone tends to their compatriots.
The Italians over there.
The Spaniards over there.
The English over there.
Yes.
The French.
We are divided by language.
Here you go...
When we were young and it was the Tridentine Mass
it was still the only true rite in the world.
We all spoke Italian.
But the liberals in "Telo" insisted on getting rid of that
"Death" of the language.
Without "Rome", without the traditions of "Rome"...
Things went downhill.
The system collapsed.
So, what, should the new pope be Italian?
Why not?
Forty years, "Thomas".
Do you think there's a compelling alternative?
Excuse me, I must go to our brothers.
The abyss calls.
It was wise of him to stay away from "Rome" until today.
If he had given one bold interview to the press
he could have made "Tedesco" undesirable.
But I think he will be successful tomorrow.
What do you mean?
I think...
He will get 15 votes in the first ballot.
And "Bellini"?
Why do I feel like a cow whose price is being set by the farmer?
The first ballot?
Between 20 and 25 votes.
But tomorrow night is when the real work will happen.
We have to somehow get him a two-thirds majority.
What exactly do you mean by "real work"?
But Your Eminence "Bellini",
those who seek the papacy...
I am not seeking the papacy.
Thank you, sisters.
Listen, you don't have to do anything.
Leave it to us.
Tell them I support a rational approach
to issues like homosexuality and divorce.
Tell them I refuse to return to the days
of the Latin liturgy
or families of ten children because the mother and father are ignorant.
That was an ugly, oppressive time,
and I'm glad it's over.
Tell them I support respecting other religions,
tolerance for other viewpoints within our church,
and tell them I believe
women should play a greater role in the clergy council.
Let's not mention women.
Why?
Brother, I have no intention
of hiding my views
or pretending to be someone I'm not
to influence any undecided member of our congregation
So...
If you wish to support my cause,
then make sure my message is clear.
I support everything that "Tedesco" does not.
Okay, if you'll excuse me.
All right.
"Rocco", talk to the Americans.
"Villanova", I'll leave South America to you.
"Gianmarco", handle the Africans.
"Aldo" does not want the position.
Any of them.
You know that, right?
Of course I know.
That's why I support him.
The dangerous men are those who want the position.
I'm enjoying all this mystery, "Thomas".
And I think you should tell me what you want to talk about.
Your last meeting with the pope.
What about it?
I've been told it was difficult.
- Was it? - Difficult? No.
I don't recall it that way.
Sorry to have to ask you
But to be more specific, I've been told
that the pope demanded your resignation.
What?
That's ridiculous. I...
Who told you that?
- Archbishop "Wozniak". - Why would he say that?
So this claim is false?
Absolutely not. That's ridiculous.
- No, okay, I had to ask. - I understand, but no.
You can ask Bishop "Morales".
He was in the meeting.
Okay, I will, but for now,
we happened to be secluded.
Can you think of a reason
why Archbishop "Wozniak" would spread such a story?
No, I can't.
Do you want coffee?
No.
I'm shocked.
- Did he tell you this himself? - Yes.
You don't think...
What?
Drinking.
I don't like to raise this issue, but we know well
that he started drinking a lot.
And it might be affecting his judgment, and even his mind.
And...
I know my name has been mentioned as the next pope,
and if the archbishop does not agree with this,
maybe he...
I don't know, I'm just trying to understand this.
Poor thing.
He was in shock because of the pope's death.
Yes, that's true.
I repeat my apologies, "Joe".
No, don't worry about it.
I completely understand.
What did you discuss with the pope
in that last meeting?
Excuse me, "Thomas."
It was a private conversation.
And very precious.
Those were the last words
I exchanged with the Pope.
Yes, of course.
Goodnight, "Joe."
Goodnight, "Thomas."
Dean.
We are neighbors, "Joshua."
It seems so.
I thought I should...
Practice more on my speech for tomorrow.
Yes, of course.
I look forward to hearing it.
I understand the trick is
not to offend anyone.
You are the responsible one.
Responsible.
"The first day of the secret conversation"
Dean "Lawrence"?
- Your Holiness.
- Everything is fine, thank you.
My dear brothers in faith,
At this moment filled with doubts
In the history of the holy church,
We must first think of the late Pope,
Whose bright papacy was
a gift from the Lord,
Now we must ask our Lord
to send us a new Pope
Through the wise guidance of the Cardinals.
And we must pray to the Lord
to provide us with that loving care,
And ask Him to guide us
To make the right choice.
But you all know that.
I want to speak from the depths of my heart for a moment.
Saint Paul said,
"Cooperate with one another
Out of respect for (Christ)."
Working together, aging together,
We should be tolerant.
Without one person or group wishing
to impose its dominance over others.
And speaking of the people of Ephesus,
Who were, of course, a mix
of Jews and Gentiles,
Paul reminds us that the gift of the Lord to the church
Is its diversity.
This diversity, this difference
in people and opinions,
Is what gives our church its strength.
And over many years,
In the service of the holy church,
allow me to tell you,
That there is one sin
I have come to fear more than others.
Certainty.
Certainty is the greatest enemy of unity.
Certainty is the deadly enemy of tolerance.
Even "Christ" was not
certain in the end.
"My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?"
He cried out in agony in
the ninth hour on the cross.
Our faith is alive because it is accompanied by doubt.
If there were certainty without doubt,
There would be no mystery.
And there would be no need for faith.
Let us pray that the Lord grants us a Pope who doubts.
And may He grant us a Pope who sins
And asks for forgiveness and continues forward.
Dean "Lawrence",
Your speech has caused a stir.
I don't think anyone expected you to...
What? To say something interesting?
I will prepare a written copy
of the speech.
If there's nothing else you need.
- Thank you.
- Your Holiness.
Yes...
I want you to do something for me.
Bishop "Morales."
I am sure he is still in "Rome."
- Can you meet him?
- Today? Well, I...
Use my authority.
I want to know what happened
at the last meeting
Between Cardinal "Tremblay" and the Pope.
What happened?
Specifically, did anything happen
that might make him unfit for the Papacy?
Of course, Your Holiness.
Bless you.
I am Cardinal "Nakitanda"
I pledge and swear, and may the Lord help me
And this holy gospel of the Lord,
which I touch with my hand.
Everyone, leave.
My Cardinal brothers,
We will now move to the first ballot.
You will find your ballot paper in front of you.
At the top is written
whom you have chosen as Pope.
Please ensure your writing is clear.
"I invoke (Christ), who will be my judge
That my vote is given to he, in the Lord's sight
I see must be elected."
The first vote for Cardinal "Tedesco."
The second vote for Cardinal "Tedesco."
Cardinal "Tremblay."
Cardinal "Tedesco."
Cardinal "Ademi."
Cardinal "Lawrence."
Cardinal "Bellini."
Cardinal "Vilanueva."
Cardinal "Tremblay."
Cardinal "Ademi."
Cardinal "Tedesco."
Cardinal "Bellini."
Cardinal "Ademi."
And finally, Cardinal "Benitez."
The results of the first ballot are...
Cardinal "Ademi," 21 votes.
Cardinal "Tedesco," 18 votes.
Cardinal "Bellini," 17 votes.
Cardinal "Tremblay," 16 votes.
Cardinal "Lawrence," 5 votes.
And one vote for the remaining Cardinals,
the total number of votes is 31.
My Cardinal brothers,
These are the results of the first ballot.
No candidate has achieved
The necessary majority of 72 votes,
We will adjourn the meeting until the evening,
And resume voting in the morning.
Thank you.
The media have noticed the presence of the Cardinal
Whose name was not on the official list, Dean.
Cardinal "Benitez,"
So I have taken it upon myself
to draft a statement.
I have also prepared some information for you.
Ministries in "Veracruz," "Congo,"
Where he established a hospital for female victims
of sexual violence
During the first and second wars.
- Then in "Baghdad" and finally in his mission in "Kabul."
- Okay.
There were some questions regarding his resignation for health reasons,
but apparently the Pope convinced him to continue.
He served his ministry
- in some dreadful places. - Yes.
Health reasons?
Can you look into this, Ray?
It's a topic the press loves to hear.
Of course.
And the other matter, the...
Yes.
I spoke to Bishop Morales.
He was firm in his assertion
that he knows of no reason preventing Cardinal Tremblay from being the Pope.
- Thank you. - However,
would you forgive me if I said
that I didn't completely believe the Monsignor?
He was...
very firm.
My Spanish is weak, and perhaps by mistake
I gave him the impression that you had seen a document
contradicting his statement, and he said
you don't need to worry, and his exact words were...
A report? A report about what?
When was it written?
I don't know, Your Eminence.
Third place.
Not what we were hoping for.
Your sermon didn't help us at all, and neither did your five votes.
You don't have enough support to be a serious candidate.
Well, my position is an embarrassment.
If I discover who my supporters are,
I'll beg them to vote for someone else.
I'll tell them I'm voting for Aldo.
Okay.
That ensures 31 votes.
We just need to secure the majority.
The Pope's turtles.
He loved them very much.
They're from Angola.
I thought I was imagining them.
I love them, they're very intelligent.
Here they keep escaping and getting run over.
We need to return, curfew begins in the evening.
And your health, how are you?
My health is in excellent condition. Thank you.
I mean, have you recovered from your journey?
- Yes. - Good.
And in the Sistine Chapel, did you find someone to vote for?
Yes. I voted for you.
Forgive me. Wasn't I supposed to say?
No, it's not that...
No, it's an honor for me, but dear Vincent...
May I call you Vincent?
I'm not a serious candidate.
My mission lies...
After the conference, I hope to resign from my position as dean
and then leave Rome permanently.
Why?
I've faced difficulties.
Regarding your faith?
Prayer.
I only mentioned it to clarify
my point that I am in no way qualified to be Pope.
Come.
Aldo.
Aldo?
I regret that my meager tally
of votes may have come at your expense.
I didn't know you were so ambitious.
That's a ridiculous thing to say.
Really?
I thought we had your support.
If we liberals don't unite, Tedesco will become Pope.
You have no idea how bad the situation is, Thomas.
The way he and his followers attacked the Pope recently.
The defamation, the leaks to the press.
It was brutal.
He fought him every day of his papacy.
And now that he's dead,
he wants to destroy the work he spent his life building.
If Tedesco becomes Pope,
it will roll back 60 years of progress.
You're speaking as if you're the only alternative.
- Well... - But Adeyemi has strong support.
Adeyemi? Adeyemi?
The man who believes gays should be sent to prison in this world and hell in the next?
Adeyemi is not the solution, and you know it.
If you want to defeat Tedesco...
Defeat? This is a conference, Aldo.
- It's not a war. - It is a war!
And you must choose a side!
Keep your precious doubts to your prayers.
You can't truly believe that I have any desire to become Pope.
For heaven's sake!
Every cardinal has that desire.
Every cardinal, deep down, has chosen the name
by which they want their papacy to be known.
Well, I haven’t chosen.
Deny it if you want.
But search your heart, and then tell me you haven't chosen.
"The second day of the conclave"
The results of the second ballot are...
Cardinal Adeyemi, 34 votes.
Cardinal Tedesco, 25 votes.
Cardinal Bellini, 18 votes.
Cardinal Tremblay, 16 votes.
Cardinal Lawrence, 9 votes.
Cardinal Benitez, 2 votes.
Brothers, according to the Apostolic Constitution,
we shall immediately proceed to the next vote.
Thank you.
The results of the third ballot are...
Cardinal Adeyemi, 52 votes.
Cardinal Tedesco, 30 votes.
Cardinal Tremblay, 10 votes.
Cardinal Bellini...
Brothers.
Please.
Thank you.
Cardinal Bellini, 9 votes.
Cardinal Lawrence, 5 votes.
Cardinal Benitez, 4 votes.
I believe something has happened.
There was an explosion, Your Eminence, in Piazza Barberini.
- A bomb? - The details are unclear at the moment.
There are injuries.
But no word of fatalities.
We must not inform the cardinal electors about this, Ray.
We are secluded, and they must be protected.
‫من كل الأخبار التي قد
‫تؤثر على حكمهم.
‫- هل فهمت؟
‫- بالطبع يا سماحتك.
‫هذا ما أعتقده.
‫ماذا عليّ أن أخبرهم في "ميلانو"
‫عندما يبدأون باكتشاف
‫وجهات النظر البابا الجديد؟
‫أخبر طائفتك أن عليهم الإحتفال
‫بأول بابا أفريقي في تاريخ الكنيسة.
‫لو كان "أديمي" أبيضًا،
‫سندينه جميعًا باعتباره
‫أكثر رجعية من "تيديسكو".
‫- فقط لأنه ليس أبيضًا...
‫- لقد فات الأوان لذلك.
‫لقد فات الأوان.
‫ماذا حدث؟
‫مساء الخير آختاه.
‫أريد التحدث مع الراهبة
‫- التي أسقطت صينيتها للتو.
‫- إنها بأمان معي.
‫أنا أتعامل مع الوضع أيها العميد.
‫أنا متأكد من ذلك يا أخت "أغنيس"،
‫لكن عليّ رؤيتها بنفسي.
‫من غير المحتمل أن يشكل
‫سقوط صينية قلق الكرادلة.
‫مع ذلك، أنا...
‫رعاية الأخت هي مسؤوليتي.
‫وهذا المجمع ملكي.
‫اجلسي رجاءً يا ابنتي.
‫اسمي الكاردينال "لورانس".
‫- كيف تشعرين؟
‫- إنها تشعر بتحسن.
‫هل يمكنكِ أن تخبريني باسمكِ؟
‫"شانومي". اسمها "شانومي".
‫اجلسي رجاءً.
‫أعتقد حقًا أنه سيكون من الأفضل
‫لو جعلتني التعامل مع الموقف...
‫هل يمكنكِ أن تتركينا الآن
‫أيتها الأخت "أغنيس"؟
‫أيتها الأخت "شانومي"،
‫أريدكِ أن تعرفي أولاً
‫أنّكِ لستِ في مشكلة.
‫الحقيقة هي أن لدي مسؤولية أمام الرب
‫لضمان أن القرارات التي نتخذها هنا
‫هي المناسبة.
‫الآن، من المهم أن تخبريني
‫بأي شيء في أعماق قلبكِ
‫أو أن هناك ما يقلقكِ،
‫فيما يتعلق بالكاردينال "أدييمي".
‫هل يمكنكِ فعل ذلك لأجلي؟
‫حتى لو أعطيتكِ تأكيداتي أن كلامنا
‫سيبقى محصورًا في هذه الغرفة فقط؟
‫هل تريدين مني أن أسمع اعترافكِ؟
‫سأكون جاهزًا بعد قليل أيها العميد.
ترجمة
"محمود بشار"
‫- ألا ينبغي لنا الرحيل؟
‫- بعد قليل.
‫يبدو أن ذلك يبعث على القلق.
‫إذا كان الأمر يتعلق بالحادث في الطابق الأسفل،
‫فليس لدي الرغبة في التحدث بالأمر.
‫أنا ضحية مؤامرة مخزية لتدمير سمعتي.
‫جلب أحدهم تلك المرأة إلى هنا
‫وأعد هذه الدراما المفتعلة.
‫لم تغادر "نيجيريا" قبلاً،
‫وفجأةً هي هنا في كنيسة "سانتا مارتا"...
‫مع كامل الإحترام يا "جوشوا"،
‫كيف أتت إلى هنا هو أمر ثانوي
‫إلى مسألة علاقتك بها.
‫لا أملك علاقة بها!
‫لم أراها منذ 30 عامًا
‫حتى أتت إلى غرفتي الليلة الماضية!
‫لقد كان خطاءً غير مقصود أيها العميد.
‫خطاءً غير مقصود.
‫"فليمنحنا الرب بابا يخطئ
‫ويطلب المغفرة ويستمر في المضي قدماً"
‫- هذا كلامك.
‫- والطفل؟
‫الطفل؟
‫نشأ الطفل في أسرة مسيحية.
‫وإلى يومنا هذا، ليس لديه أيّ فكرة
‫عن من هو والده.
‫إذا كان أنا حقًا.
‫هذا هو الطفل.
‫لقد كنا صغارًا.
‫لا يا "جوشوا".
‫كانت صغيرة جدًا،
‫كان عمرها 19 عامًا.
‫- لقد كان عمرك 30.
‫- "توماس".
‫"توماس".
‫إستمع ليّ. أرجوك.
‫لقد شعرت بحضور
‫الروح القدس هذا الصباح،
‫أقسم بذلك.
‫أنا مستعد لتحمل هذا العبء.
‫هل خطأ واحد منذ 30 عام
‫يجعلني غير مؤهل؟
‫أرجوك با "توماس".
‫لقد كنت رجلاً مختلفًا.
‫أتوسل إليك ألا تستخدم
‫هذه المعلومة لتدميرني.
‫"جوشوا"، هذه الفكرة لا تليق بك.
‫"شانومي" لن تتفوه بحرف
‫حتى تحمي ابنها.
‫وأنا مقيد بنذور سر الاعتراف.
‫إذن لا يزال ليّ أمل.
‫لا.
‫لا يوجد أمل.
‫بعد هذا التصرف أمام العامة،
‫ستكون هناك شائعات،
‫وأنت تعرف طبيعة مجلس الكهنة.
‫لا شيء يرعب زملاءنا أكثر من فكرة
‫المزيد من الفضائح الجنسية.
‫أنا آسف للغاية.
‫لن تصبح بابا أبدًا.
‫عليك أن تبدأ من جديد.
‫ولكنك رجل صالح.
‫أعرف أنّك رجل صالح،
‫وستجد طريقة للتكفير عن ذنبك.
‫هلا تصلي معي؟
‫نعم بالطبع.
‫نتائج الاقتراع الخامس هي...
‫الكاردينال "تريمبلاي"، 40 صوتًا.
‫الكاردينال "تيديسكو"، 34 صوتًا.
‫الكاردينال "بيليني"، 30 صوت.
‫الكاردينال "لورانس"، 11 صوتًا.
‫الكاردينال "أديمي"، 9 أصوات.
‫الكاردينال "بينيتيز"، 6 أصوات.
‫أخوتي...
‫إخوتي، بهذا ننتهي
‫من الجولة الخامسة من التصويت.
‫لم يحصل أيّ مرشح
‫على الأغلبية اللازمة
‫سنستأنف التصويت غدًا صباحًا.
‫نعم يا "راي"؟
‫الحادثة التي وقعت
‫صباح اليوم يا سماحتك.
‫لدي المزيد من المعلومات إذا...
‫لا، يجب أن أكون محميًا أيضًا
‫من أي معرفة
‫قد تؤثر على سير الاجتماع السري.
‫بالطبع يا سماحتك.
‫هل هناك شيء آخر؟
‫الكاردينال "بينيتيز".
‫مشاكله الصحية.
‫تم تزويده بتذكرة
‫ذهاب وعودة إلى "جنيف"،
‫مدفوعة من حساب البابا الخاص.
‫لقد تحققت من طلب التأشيرة خاصته.
‫وكان الغرض من السفر
‫هو "العلاج الطبي".
‫على أية حال، مهما كان سبب السفر،
‫فلا بد أنه كان سببًا مهمًا.
‫لقد تم إلغاء التذكرة
‫ولم يذهب أبدًا.
‫حسناً، شكراً لك.
‫سامحني يا سماحتك.
‫أعلم أّنك قلت أن علينا
‫نسيان أمر
‫- التقرير المسحوب.
‫- نعم.
‫ولكنني تساءلت،
‫في ضوء موقف الكاردينال
‫"تريمبلاي" الحالي...
‫يمكنني أن أحاول اكتشاف
‫إذا كان بإمكاني معرفة...
‫لا، لستُ باحثًا عن السحرة.
‫عملي ليس البحث
‫عن أسرار زملائي القديمة.
‫سامحني.
Please stop the investigations.
I...
I believe we've heard enough secrets.
Let's leave the rest to God.
Yes, of course.
Good night, Your Eminence.
Is this really necessary?
I feel like I'm in an American political convention.
It won't take long.
Our friend here doesn't have enough support among our colleagues to be elected Pope.
The voting isn't over yet.
I'm afraid it's over for me.
And now the question arises:
If I can't win,
who do I advise my supporters to vote for?
"Thomas," I'm not more enthusiastic about "Tremblay" than you are.
But we have to face the reality...
We have to face the reality that he has shown broad popularity.
- He might be the one to unite us. - No, no.
- He might be the person who unites us.
- No, no.
- What? - Is this what we've come to?
Considering the least bad option?
But the choices have become few.
If we don't change our vote, we'll be here for weeks.
And that's exactly what "Tedesco" wants.
We once had a Pope who was a member of "Hitler Youth" and fought for the Nazis.
We've accused Popes of colluding with communists and fascists.
We've had Popes who overlooked reports of child sexual abuse!
Okay.
We get your point.
The point is we'll never find a candidate without a dark past.
We are mortal men.
We serve an ideal principle.
We can't always be perfect.
So we've agreed.
We'll urge all our supporters to support "Tremblay."
Good.
Last night, you were kind enough
to say that you voted for me.
I don't know if you continued to do so,
but if you are still doing so, I must repeat my plea to you to stop.
Why?
First, I lack the spiritual depth to be Pope.
Second, I can't win.
The media will consider the lengthy conclave
as evidence that the Church is in crisis.
Did you come to ask me to vote for Cardinal "Tremblay"?
Yes, I did, and urge your supporters to do the same.
Cardinal "Tremblay" spoke to me about this.
I'm sure he did.
Do you want me to vote for a man you see as ambitious?
I don't want "Tedesco" to be Pope.
He will take our Church back to an earlier era.
I'm sorry, but I can't vote for a man
unless I consider him the most worthy of the papacy.
And for me, that man isn't "Tremblay."
It's you.
I don't want your vote!
And yet, you will have it.
Sister "Shanome" is on her way to Nigeria.
There was a flight to Lagos this evening,
and I thought it best for everyone if she was on it.
How did Sister "Shanome" come to Rome?
I received notice from the Superior General's office
that she would be joining us.
The arrangement was made in Paris.
You should ask "Buck," Your Eminence.
I would have done so, of course,
but I've been isolated during the secret meeting.
So you should ask them after the meeting ends.
This information is valuable to me now.
Sister "Agnes," I know you were close to the Pope.
When I tried to resign as Dean, he wouldn't allow it.
I didn't understand why at the time, but now I think I do.
I think the Pope knew he was dying,
and for some reason, he wanted me to manage this secret meeting.
That's what I'm trying to do.
For him.
I want you to withdraw your name from the next vote.
You're not the right man to be Pope.
40 of our colleagues might disagree with you on that.
That's because they don't know you as I do.
That's sad, "Thomas."
I'll pray for you.
I know there's a report about your activities.
I know the Pope discussed it with you hours before his death
and that he expelled you from all your positions,
and I know you somehow discovered
"Ademi's" succumbing to temptation 30 years ago
and that you orchestrated bringing the woman in question to Rome for a specific purpose
to destroy "Ademi's" chances of becoming Pope.
I deny this accusation.
Do you deny asking the abbess to transfer a sister to Rome?
No, I asked her.
- But not on my behalf. - Well, on whose behalf then?
The Pope.
Will you falsely accuse the Pope in his own house?
It's not slander.
It's the truth.
The Pope gave me a sister's name
and asked me to make a special request to bring her to Rome.
I had no idea why, and now I've chosen...
You must be careful, "Thomas."
Your ambition hasn't gone unnoticed.
This could be seen as a tactic to smear the name of a competitor.
Well, that's a vile accusation.
Is it?
I wonder...
if you're really hesitant
to see the papacy handed to you.
I'll pretend this conversation never happened.
But it did happen!
This is a report on "Tremblay's" activities.
The case appears at first glance
to be conclusive evidence of his committing the crime of simony, which is, of course,
a crime specified in the Bible...
I know what simony is. Thank you.
He got all those votes in the first ballot because he bought them.
"Cardenas," "Dieni," "Figarella," "Baptist."
And all this happened in the last 12 months
when he must have realized the Pope would soon die.
How can we be sure this money wasn't used for entirely legal purposes?
Because I haven't seen any bank statements.
My God.
It seems the Pope was watching us all.
He trusted no one.
Where did you get this?
I broke the seals.
I felt I had no choice.
I felt like I didn't have a choice.
I suspected Tremblay of having brought that poor woman from Africa to embarrass Adeyemi.
You have to keep running, Aldo.
Put them back where they belong.
Or burn them or...
Just put them back where they belong.
There is no way I could become a pope under these circumstances.
Document theft and defamation
One of the Cardinal&#39;s brothers?
I&#39;d be the Richard Nixon of popes.
So leave this to me.
I am ready to bear the consequences.
Do you know who will benefit the most?
&quot;Tedesco&quot;.
The essence of his candidacy is that the Pope has brought the Church to disaster.
With his reform attempts.
If you disclose this report,
Tremblay&#39;s reputation will not be affected.
But the reputation of the church.
The Council of Priests is accused of institutional corruption.
I thought we were here to serve the Lord, not the priesthood.
Don&#39;t be naive.
Put them back where they belong.
And &quot;Tremblay&quot; is the Pope?
We&#39;ve had worse people.
What did he offer you?
Minister of State?
I voted for you 5 times, Aldo.
But I was wrong.
You lack the courage to be a pope.
&quot;The third day of the secret meeting&quot;
mistake&quot;
I will do it for you, Your Eminence.
How many copies do you want?
‫108.
You are responsible for this I think.
No, Your Eminence. You are the one responsible.
This report is a lie!
It would never have come out into the open if it hadn&#39;t been for
She breaks into the Pope&#39;s apartment to take him away!
If the report is false, why did the Pope do it?
In his last official act as Pope, he asked you to resign?
He didn&#39;t do this.
As Bishop Morales, who was present at the meeting, said...
However, Archbishop Wozniak insists that the Pope...
May the Pope be honored among the chief priests,
He was a sick man at the end of his life,
As those of us who have seen him
regularly can attest.
If you would allow me to join this friendly conversation.
I want to remind you
The names of eight cardinals have been withheld.
Their names have been removed!
I think the dean
can tell us their names?
To tell us who they are
Here and now.
If Cardinal Tremblay asks for their votes
In exchange for money...
No, I wouldn&#39;t do that.
Let every man examine his conscience as I did.
I have no intention of creating tension
in this meeting.
I would be happy to step down as Dean.
Do you see? Do you see?
Your Eminence!
Your Eminence.
Even though we sisters are supposed to be invisible,
Yet the Lord has given us eyes and ears.
I know what prompted the dean to enter the Pope&#39;s room.
He was worried that my sister-in-law had caused that unfortunate incident.
It may have been brought to Rome on purpose.
To embarrass any member of this meeting.
His suspicions were correct.
She actually came here
On specific request
From Cardinal Tremblay.
My brothers,
This is correct.
But the Pope asked me to.
I didn&#39;t know who this woman was,
I swear to you.
Judah&quot;.
traitor
It seems we have no supporters left.
You have to take charge of supervising this election, Aldo.
No thank you.
You will lead this meeting.
Where exactly, I don&#39;t know.
But it seems your strictness has its admirers.
&quot;Thomas,&quot; I came to ask your forgiveness.
I had the audacity
To tell you to check your heart,
When all the time,
was...
It&#39;s a shame.
To be at this age
and not know yourself yet.
Ambition is the moth of holiness.
I&#39;m sorry.
Maybe it&#39;s time to come up with a name.
As the oldest member of this forum,
I have to ask you
how you would like to be known as Papa.
For or against us,
It seems that the &quot;Tremblay&quot; thing is over.
This is a contest between you and Tedesco.
You&#39;re the only one who can stop him now.
June&quot;.
I will choose the name &quot;John&quot;.
&quot;The Pope chose&quot;
Everyone was taken to the house of Saint Martha, Your Eminence.
No one was seriously hurt, just a few cuts.
Outside the city, how bad is it?
Oh, my God.
At 11:20 am today,
A car bomb exploded in Al-Nahda Square.
Shortly after, as people were fleeing the scene,
Individual carrying explosives on his body
He blew himself up.
There are reports of further attacks in both Leuven and Munich.
The current death toll is...
52 dead.
Hundreds were injured.
Okay then.
Here at last we see the result of the doctrine of relativity.
Which our liberal brothers love!
Relativism sees all religions and temporary beliefs
Treated the same.
Even now when we look around
We see the land of the Holy Roman Catholic Church
It is full of mosques and minarets.
To Prophet &quot;Muhammad&quot;!
- You should be ashamed.
- Ashamed?
- We should all be ashamed!
We tolerate Islam in our land,
But they curse us in themselves.
We feed them in our homelands.
‫لكنهم يبيدوننا.
‫إلى متى سنستمر في هذا الضعف؟
‫هم حرفيًا على أبوابنا الآن.
‫ما نحتاجه الآن هو قائد يفهم
‫أننا نواجه حربًا دينية
‫لا تلمسني!
‫نعم، حرب دينية.
‫نحن بحاجة إلى قائد
‫يضع حداً للانجراف
‫الذي استمر بلا انقطاع تقريبًا
‫على مدى السنوات الخمسين الماضية.
‫إلى متى سنستمر في هذا الضعف،
‫إلى متى؟
‫نحن بحاجة إلى قائد...
‫يقاتل هؤلاء الحيوانات!
‫هل هذا هو الرجل
‫الذي تريدون أن يقودنا؟
‫أخي الكاردينال.
‫مع كامل الاحترام...
‫ماذا تعرف عن الحرب؟
‫لقد خدمت وزارتي في "الكونغو".
‫في "بغداد" و"كابول".
‫رأيت صفوف القتلى والجرحى،
‫مسيحيون ومسلمون.
‫عندما تقول علينا أن نقاتل،
‫ما الذي تعتقد أن علينا مقاتلته؟
‫هل تظن أن هؤلاء الرجال الضالين
‫هم من نفذوا هذه الأعمال الرهيبة اليوم؟
‫لا يا أخي.
‫المسألة أنّك تقاتل بقلبك...
‫بداخلنا جميعًا،
‫إذا استسلمنا إلى الكره الآن،
‫إذا تحدثنا من "الجانبين"
‫بدلاً من التحدث نيابةً
‫عن كل رجل وامرأة.
‫هذه هي المرة الأولى ليّ هنا بينكم،
‫وأعتقد أنها الأخيرة.
‫سامحوني، ولكن في الأيام القليلة الماضية
‫أظهرنا أنفسنا وكأننا رجال صغار تافهون،
‫لقد بدأ أننا مهتمون فقط بأنفسنا،
‫بـ "روما"،
‫بهذه الانتخابات والسلطة.
‫لكن هذه الأمور لا تمثل الكنيسة.
‫الكنيسة ليست تقليد.
‫الكنيسة ليست الماضي.
‫الكنيسة هي ما سنفعله بعد ذلك.
‫نحن نصلي،
‫أبانا حتى ترشدنا
‫واحرس كنيستك
‫امنحنا، نحن خدمك
‫نعمة العقل والحق والسلام.
‫لكي نجتهد في معرفة مشيئتك،
‫ونخدمك بكل تفانٍ.
‫لأجل "المسيح" ربنا.
‫آمين.
‫"بيليني".
‫"بينيتيز".
‫"لورانس".
‫"تيديسكو".
‫هل تقبل انتخابك الكنسي لمنصب البابا؟
‫نعم.
‫وبأي اسم تريد أن تُلقب به؟
‫"البريء".
‫"الانتخابات البابوية العليا"
‫سيادة المطران.
‫اعتذر على المقاطعة.
‫"راي".
‫أعتقد أنه يجب عليك جمع
‫ملاحظات الكرادلة.
‫كلما بدأنا في وقت أقرب،
‫كلما عرف العالم
‫أن لدينا بابا جديداً.
‫ما الأمر؟
‫لم تكن...
‫لم تكن النتيجة التي توقعتها.
‫لا، لكنها رائع على أية حال.
‫إذا كنت قلقًا بشأن موقفي،
‫يمكنني أن أطمئنك
‫أنّني لا أشعر سوى بالارتياح.
‫بابانا الجديد سيكون افضّل مني بمراحل.
‫أتساءل عما إذا كان بإمكاني
‫التحدث معك على انفراد.
‫كان ينبغي ليّ أن أخبرك
‫هذا الصباح عندما اكتشفت ذلك،
‫ولكن مع كل...
‫ولم احلم
‫أن الكاردينال "بينيتيز" سيصبح...
‫"راي"، أخبرني ماذا يقلقك.
‫لقد اكتشفت...
‫"سويسرا".
‫رحلة الكاردينال "بينيتيز" إلى "سويسرا".
‫"سويسرا". المستشفى في "جنيف"، صحيح؟
‫لم يكن مستشفى.
‫لقد كانت عيادة.
‫عيادة لماذا؟
‫سماحتك، لن يلبس قداسته الرداء.
‫مسموح ليّ.
‫- هل يمكنني تلتحدث معك على انفراد؟
‫- بالطبع.
‫يا سادة، لنخرج من الغرفة.
‫كنت أنتظر مجيئك.
‫عليك أن تخبرني عن هذا العلاج
‫في العيادة في "جنيف".
‫- هل عليّ ذلك أيها العميد؟
‫- نعم، عليك ذلك.
‫في غضون ساعة، سوف تصبح
‫الرجل الأكثر شهرة في العالم،
‫لذا أخبرني رجاءً.
‫ما هي حالتك الطبية؟
‫حالتي، كما قلت،
‫إنها نفسها ما كانت عليه
‫عندما تم تعييني كاهنًا.
‫وعندما أصبحت كاردينالاً.
‫ولكن العلاج في "جنيف"؟
‫لم يكن هناك علاج.
‫لقد فكرت في الأمر.
‫لقد دعوت الرب أن يهديني
‫وقررت عدم خوض العلاج.
‫ولكن ما هو هذا العلاج؟
‫اسمه استئصال الرحم باستخدام المنظار.
‫يتوجب عليك أن تفهم.
‫عندما كنت طفلاً، لم يكن هناك وسيلة
‫لمعرفة أن وضعي كان أكثر تعقيدًا.
‫والحياة في المدرسة الدينية،
‫كما تعلم، متواضعة للغاية.
‫الحقيقة هي أنه لم يكن هناك
‫سبب للتفكير
‫أنّني كنت مختلفًا جسديًا
‫عن بقية الشباب الآخرين.
‫وفي أواخر الثلاثينيات من عمري،
‫أجريت عملية جراحية
‫لإزالة الزائدة الدودية.
‫وهنا اكتشف الأطباء
‫أن لدي رحم.
‫ومبايض.
‫قد يقول البعض أن كروموسومياتي
‫هي التي ستحدد هويتي
‫بأنّي امرأة.
‫ولكنني أيضًا كما تراني.
‫لقد كان وقتًا مظلمًا ليّ.
‫شعرت وكأن حياتي كلها ككاهن
‫عاش في حالة من الخطيئة.
‫وبطبيعة الحال،
‫قدمت استقالتي للبابا.
‫سافرت إلى "روما" وأخبرته بكل شيء.
‫هل كان يعلم؟
‫نعم. كان يعلم.
‫ورأى أنه من المقبول أن تستمر
‫كوزير مُرسَم؟
‫فكرنا في إجراء عملية جراحية
‫لإزالة الأجزاء الأنثوية من جسدي.
‫ولكن في الليلة التي سبقت
‫موعد رحلتي،
‫أدركت أنّني كنت مخطئًا.
‫كنت الشخص الذي كنت عليه دائمًا.
‫شعرت أن أكبر خطيئة
‫أن أغير خلق الرب
‫من أن أترك جسدي كما كان عليه.
‫إذن أنت لا تزال...
‫أنا ما خلقني الرب عليه.
‫وربما يكون اختلافي
‫هو الذي سيجعلني أكثر فائدة.
‫أفكر مجددًا في خطبتك.
‫أدرك ما يعني أن أعيش
‫بين تأكيدات العالم.
ترجمة
"محمود بشار"